Toby Bessant - Curriculum Vitae

Date of Birth 13/04/1998 Telephone 07538 955566

Email toby.bessant@tobybessant.co.uk

GitHub github.com/tobybessant Portfolio tobybessant.co.uk

Profile

Progressive and client-focused full-stack developer experienced in producing robust applications across an array of technologies. Demonstrable understanding of software development fundamentals, in addition to a multitude of newer frameworks and libraries. Undertaken an industry placement year working under agile methodologies to integrate & automate business web-applications. Always exploring new ideas through tangible projects including a mobile tenancy communication platform, web-based multi-player typing game, and a noise-based procedural terrain generator.

Professional Experience

2018–2019

Business Applications Developer | A2Z Cloud

Placement year taken as part of my degree. Configured, automated, and integrated various Zoho and external business applications.

- Developed **NodeJS** middlewares to sync and map relational-database records to formats received by business applications.
- Hosted applications using AWS lambda.
- Used various REST API's & webhooks to connect services.
- Attended and ran weekly client meetings, both for requirements gathering and app demos.
- Took part in daily **scrum** meetings, even having the opportunity to run a scrum meeting when my manager was unavailable.

2015-2016

Customer Assisstant | The Regal Stowmarket

Part-time job during college to improve confidence and start earning some personal finances.

- Selling box office tickets, answering customer calls, working behind the bar
- Developed good communication skills due to small team of 3 at all times.
- Small team size meant I took part in marketing decisions and am proud to say that their growth led to plans of expansion after my departure.

Education

2016–2020 | Computing & Games Development BSc (Hons), University of Plymouth.

Predicted to graduate with first-class honours

2014–2016 **A-Levels, Suffolk One Sixth-form College.**

Computing: D, Sociology: B, Psychology: D, Ancient History AS: D

2009–2014 | GCSE's, Stradbroke High School.

English: B Core Science: B ICT: Pass
Maths: B Additional Science: B History: A
Religious Studies: A* Business Studies: B Graphics: C

Skills Profile

Software development: Agile (scrum), SOLID principles, GoF Design Patterns, TDD

Languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Web frameworks: TypeScript, Express, TypeORM, Mocha, VueJS, Angular8, SCSS, Cordova, Ionic

Database: SQLServer, MongoDB **Version control:** Git, GitHub, Bitbucket **CI/CD:** Docker, Azure Pipelines, Heroku

As a result of my university degree I have experience developing in a wide range of languages, environments, and disciplines. The first two years of my degree were centred around building a foundation for my programming skills, using C# and Java to demonstrate SOLID principles and implement design patterns to solve problems. As I have matured as a developer my primary interest has shifted towards full-stack web development. In my own time I started to teach myself about web development, and carried these skills into my final year at university. Since then, I have experience developing in JavaScript and TypeScript to produce APIs & persistence layers, communicating to both MongoDB and relational databases. My front-end development experience spans the use of VueJS and Angular8, for desktop web applications and native mobile applications. I have experience using Git in both individual and team settings, performing and receiving pull-requests and code reviews with my colleagues.

Between my second and third years of university, I was able to use the skills I had learnt in an industry environment - automating and integrating business web-applications for clients. Working in an agile environment meant I was involved with scrum meetings, and directly demonstrating my solutions to clients over online meetings on a weekly basis. My placement gave me skills in programming and debugging in a web environment, in addition to working with APIs, databases, and building integration middleware. This middleware was often hosted on AWS which I would help configure. I would also be on the client support portal, emailing and calling clients to assist them with any problems they were experiencing. On a personal level, my placement year improved my confidence which in turn has helped with my ability to approach new challenges.

In addition to the skills outlined above, I have experience using C# to develop experience-based projects in Unity3D - allowing me to utilise my programming knowledge to make games, and VR experiences. During my final year of university I used C++ and OpenGL to build various graphics rendering applications; a model-loader to parse and render the data for 3D model files, and an application to procedurally generate & render virtual terrains using noise functions.

Interests

Outside of software development I have a keen interest in reading fiction books, particularly of the crime-fiction genre. I enjoy it because it provides a way for me to be analytical and test my problem solving abilities in an atypical way. In addition, I enjoy learning about ancient history - particularly Ancient Rome and Ancient Greece, as these eras of human history are responsible for many of our traditions today. In my spare time I play guitar, which feeds into an active interest in music - something which has had a large influence on my life.

References

References available on request.